CURRICULAM VITAE

Name : **RAGHUPATHY**

Experien

: 09 Years 06 Months

ce

: Electrical Project Engineer

Position E mail

: raghurajkumar@outlook.com

Mobile

+91-9597350616 & 7094254167

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:-

More than 09 years experience (up to 400kV) as project engineer, directing developmental project teams throughout entire process culminating in successful completion. A competent Project Engineer with excellent communication, organisation and co-ordination skills. Possessing a proven track record of preparing and executing project plans and programmes, ensuring that work is carried out in accordance with the companies procedures and clients satisfaction. Able to ensure timely, safe and cost effective design and implementation during the life cycle of projects from conception till customer satisfaction.

Well versed with various International codes and standards. I have been working with a multinational public listed company in Middle East.

KEY SKILLS

- ➤ Highly experienced in using various project management tools for scheduling, delegating responsibilities and collecting information.
- > Skilled in budget management, forecast, cost estimation and goal setting.
- > Technical knowledge on the [project areas].
- > Polished presentation.

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION:-

➤ Bachelor of Technology Electrical Engineering Year of Completion Jan 2016.

➤ **Diploma In Electrical and Electronics Engineering** Year of Completion April 2006.

CAREER HISTORY

Organization: M/s. KASS Contracting Pvt Ltd. Tanjore India.

Designation : Electrical Project Engineer Period : December 2015 - Present

Organization : M/s. National Contracting Company Pvt Ltd. Abu Dhabi,

UAE.

Designation : Electrical Project Engineer
Period : September 2008 to October 2015

Organization: M/s. TamilNadu Electricity Board India.

Designation : Testing and Commissioning Engineer

Period : April 2007 to April 2008

PROJECTS DETAILS

• 33kV/11kV local distributions (TNEB, Regular Maintenance Tanjore), India. Local Distribution. India.

- 132kV & 33kV Overhead Transmission Line, Substation power network upgrade BAB Habsan, Abu Dhabi, UAE
- 33kV substation- 40 km Transmission Line 4no's wells at gusawhira, Abu Dhabi, UAE.
- 33kV Substation modification works H01 & H22 feeder & 28km Over Head Transmission Line from Bu Hasa to Bidal Qamzan, , Abu Dhabi, UAE.
- 220kV & 33kV AIS substations, Algeria.
- 400kV Transmission and Distribution line, 132kV Cable laying works DEWA, UAE.
- 400kV/220/110kV Substation and Transmission and Distribution line, Tamil Nadu, India.

RESPONSIBILITIES:-

- ➤ Provided support during installation and start-up of projects, ensuring multidiscipline engineering and design efforts were completed in accordance with project scope, schedule, and costs.
- Checked construction and engineering contractors' performance against specifications, codes, and drawings.
- ➤ Verified construction work was performed safely per company, industry, and regulatory standards.
- ➤ Managed schedule to make sure projects were completed per estimates. Responsible for overseeing the review, initiation and execution of contracts.
- ➤ Prepared and presented project status and progress reports, successful Planning, organizing, estimating, scheduling and monitoring site work activities.
- Assisted with project technical supervision, cost estimating, materials selection, quality assurance, transition planning, approval procurement, and project close-out documentation.
- ➤ Helped develop and execute engineering and construction projects with focus on integrating design and construction area.
- Aided in scheduling of draftspersons, engineering aides, and other engineers.
- ➤ Designing, Installation testing procedures and coordinate client, Document results, and develop client presentation.

- Evaluate selection and Appling standard techniques and procedures to perform engineering assignments. Provides technical support for testing, installation and commissioning activities.
- ➤ Providing technical assistance to integrate Design based commissioning and Construction based implementation.
- > Supervise and monitoring works, installation, testing, and inspection carried out at site as per standards.
- ➤ Liaising with customers on a regular basis to ensure the successful design and manufacture of products to agreed budgets and time frames.
- ➤ Sub Contract documents verification, test plan as per ITP, HSE regulation implementation at site.
- ➤ Identify and propose improvements to existing electrical systems write reports detailing current systems and changes to each site.
- ➤ Prepare test reports, FAT reports, failure reports, QC observations conduct and lead the FATs (Factory Acceptance Tests) with/without customer's inspections.
- ➤ Install Switchyard, Transformer, Cable Laying, Inverter, Switchgear, HT Panel, LT panel.
- ➤ Skilled to test and commission all types of switch yard and switch gear equipments such as Current Transformer, Capacitive Voltage Transformer, Circuit Breaker, Isolator, Earth Switch and Lighting arresters, Generator Transformer, Unit Transformer, Capacitor banks, Motor(VFD).
- ➤ Skilled in all types of scheme checking such as transformer protection, motor protection, differential schemes, stability schemes, capacitor bank stage controls and interlocks and other control circuit schemes with various systems.
- ➤ Skilled to test various Numerical protection relays of ABB, Siemens, General Electric, Eesun reyrolle, C&S make having protections such as Differential Protection, Earth Fault, Over current, Negative Phase Sequence Current, Earth fault, Thermal overload protection, Under voltage and Over voltage protections.
- Experienced to do HV Test for Power Cables and Bus bars rated up to 400kV.
- ➤ Knowledge of all Differential Protection such as Power Transformer, Generator Transformer, reactor, generator, motor, Cable, Bus bar and REF Protection.
- ➤ Preparing inspection Schedule with consultant for system approval. Coordinating with client, consultant, contractor, subcontractor and supplier.
- ➤ PTW, LOA, Tag-In ,Tag-Out, Padlock System, Hot Permit and Cold Permits for Safety formalities for all kind of Electrical Work.

➤ Preparing Test packs and Ready for Inspection (RFI) schedule for consultant approval and Compliance with necessary standards as per the client requirements.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:-

- ➤ Well-versed with MS-Office, MS Project, AutoCAD, Primavera P6, ETAP, PLC, SCADA.
- > The ability to interface effectively with clients, employees, and management team is Essential.

CERTIFICATIONS / PROFESSIONAL ENHANCEMENTS:-

- > Project Management Professional Training (PMP).
- > Primavera P6.
- ➤ EHV (Primary & Secondary) Electrical system designing by ADEI at Delhi.

AWARDS AND RECOGNITIONS:-

- Seven Years' Service Achievement Award NCC, UAE.
- > Primavera Super User.

PERSONNEL DETAILS:-

Name : R. Raghupathy

Date of Birth : 03/04/1986

Father Name : D. Rajkumar

Gender : Male

Marital Status : Married

Nationality : Indian

Language : Tamil, English, Arabic (Little)

Passport : PO420117

DECLARATION:-

I hereby declare that the above furnished information is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Place: Trichyyours faithfully,Date:(Raghupathy.R)